(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-pro-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
Natsuiro Matsuri 2020
アイドル革命進行中！
Idol Revolution in Progress!
世界一可愛い
The cutest in the world.
宇宙一可愛い
The cutest in the universe.
もっともっと聞かせて
Let me hear it more and more.
ご褒美は目を閉じて
For your reward, close your eyes...
ちゅ！
Mwah!
見つけてくれてサンキュー
Thank you for finding me.
愛してくれてサンキュー
Thank you for loving me.
生きがいにしちゃってもいいのよ
It's okay to make me your reason for living.
一人じゃ無理だ 逆境
I can't face adversity alone,
みんながいれば最強
But with everyone, I'm invincible.
見つめ合ってよ 想い
Let's gaze at each other, these feelings...
好き！
I love you!
になっちゃえ
Fall for me!
涙じゃなにも解決しない
Tears won't solve anything,
のはわかってるから だから
I know that, so...
覚悟はいい？
Are you ready?
世界一かわいい
The cutest in the world!
宇宙一かわいい
The cutest in the universe!
もっともっときかせて
Let me hear more and more!
よそ見はダメ
Don't look away.
OK？
OK?
瞬きもかわいい
Even blinking is cute.
存在がかわいい
My existence is cute.
もっともっときかせて
Let me hear more and more!
ご褒美は…
The reward is...
目を合わせて
Look into my eyes...
チュッ！
Chu!
歌ってくれて Thank You
Thank you for singing along.
笑顔くれて Thank You
Thank you for the smiles.
生きててよかったって思った
I thought, 'I'm glad I'm alive.'
ちょっとのミスは愛嬌
A little mistake adds charm.
だけどやる気は最強
But my motivation is the strongest.
競い合って高め合って成長できる
Competing and enhancing each other, we can grow.
苦手からちょっと逃げてちゃ愛は届かないから
If I run away from my weaknesses, love won't reach you.
だから何度も
So, again and again...
何度も挑むわ
I'll challenge it again and again!
楽しんじゃおう
Let's enjoy it!
あざとくてかわいい
Cunningly cute.
最高にかわいい
Supremely cute.
私だけをロックオン
Lock on to only me.
よそ見はダメ
Don't look away.
OK？
OK?
不器用でもかわいい
Even if clumsy, I'm cute.
存在がかわいい
My existence is cute.
もっともっときかせて
Let me hear more and more!
輝くから
Because I'll shine.
約束ね
It's a promise, okay?
上手に歌えてるかな
Am I singing well?
上手に踊れてるかな
Am I dancing well?
間違えるの怖くなるけど
I get scared of making mistakes, but...
できる できる できる できる
I can do it, I can do it, I can do it...
そうだ
That's right.
信じてくれる人がいる
There are people who believe in me.
この歌で君と繋がっていられる
With this song, I can stay connected with you.
忘れられないストーリー描いてこう
Let's draw an unforgettable story.
いくよ！
Here we go!
世界一かわいい
The cutest in the world!
宇宙一かわいい
The cutest in the universe!
もっともっときかせて
Let me hear more and more!
よそ見はダメ
Don't look away.
OK？
OK?
瞬きもかわいい
Even blinking is cute.
存在がかわいい
My existence is cute.
もっともっときかせて
Let me hear more and more!
ご褒美は…
The reward is...
目を合わせて
Look into my eyes...
チュッ！
Chu!
現役アイドルちゅ～
Active Idol in Progress~
今日も鏡をチェック
Checking the mirror today too.
最高の笑顔届ける才能
The talent to deliver the best smile.
努力が大事よ
Effort is important.
ちゃんとお勉強して
Study properly.
ちゃんとお片付けする
Clean up properly.
だって私はそうアイドルだもん
Because I am, yes, an idol!
好きなタイプは私を大好きで
My favorite type is someone who loves me,
一途な人
Someone who is single-minded.
なんては妄想だけど
That's just a delusion, though...
君だけのものになれないの ああごめん
I can't be yours alone. Ah, sorry.
いつまでも好きでいて約束よ
Love me forever, it's a promise.
わがままなお願いね
It's a selfish request, isn't it?
みんなのものていたい
I want to belong to everyone.
それでも私のこと好きですか？
Do you still love me?
ピンク色のフリフリ
Pink frills.
スポットライト浴びて
Bathed in the spotlight.
いつかきっとね
Someday surely,
君だけの私に
I'll be yours alone.
今はもっと歌いたい
But now, I want to sing more.
現役アイドルちゅ～
Active Idol in Progress~
ずっとワクワクなのよ
I'm always so excited.
お洋服選ぶのもして
Choosing my clothes too,
お気に入りポーズしちゃうんだ
I strike my favorite pose.
キラキラメイクは今日もバッチリ
My sparkling makeup is perfect today too.
やっと君とデート
Finally, a date with you.
ちょっと話せるだけなのになんか
Even though we can only talk for a little bit...
なんと今日は早起きして
Surprisingly, I woke up early today.
二人の時間を楽しみにし てるから
Because I'm looking forward to our time together.
握手会 コンサート
Handshake events, concerts...
会いに来て
Come to see me.
君のハッピーなその顔
That happy face of yours,
ずっと覚えているわ
I'll remember it forever.
今週も来週も
This week and next week too,
会いたいな
I want to see you.
おしゃれなお洋服も
With stylish clothes,
準備して待ってるね
I'll get ready and wait for you.
会えなくても頑張る君のこと
Even if we can't meet, you do your best,
いつまでも好きでいる
And I'll always love that about you.
オフィシャル両思い
We're officially in mutual love.
赤と白混ぜた日にありがとう
Thank you to the day red and white mixed.
こんなにキュートな私でいちゃうもん
Because I'll stay this cute me.
くるくるレースもヒラリ回ってる
The spinning lace is fluttering around too.
いくつになってもこのまま
No matter how old I get, just like this,
ここで輝く
I will shine right here.
ねえねえ 教えて？
Hey, hey, tell me?
なあに？ 今日も可愛い？
What is it? Am I cute today?
可愛いよー！
You're cute!
いつまでも好きでいて
Keep loving me forever,
約束よ
It's a promise.
私だって君のこと
I also love you,
ずっとずっと大好き
Forever and ever.
一生私のこと
Will you love me...
好きですか
...for your whole life?
ピンク色のフリフリ
Pink frills,
スカート空に飛ばして
Flying my skirt into the sky.
いつかきっとね
Someday, surely,
君だけの私に
I'll be yours only.
今はまだ歌いたい
But right now, I still want to sing.
現役アイドル中
I'm currently an active idol!
わぁー！
Waaa!
みんな せーの！
Everyone, ready, set!
こんばんワッショイ！
Good evening-wasshoi!
どうもホロライブの清楚担当
Hello! I am Hololive's purity representative,
みんなのアイドル 夏色...
everyone's idol, Natsuiro...
まつりです！
Matsuri!
ということで今年もやってきました
So, it has come again this year!
遅ればせながらの生誕 誕生日祭でございますよ
It's the belated Birthday Festival!
まつりちゃんね 誕生日は7月の22日
Matsuri-chan's birthday is actually July 22nd,
なんでございますが
but...
まああの 周年が6月ということでね
well, since the anniversary is in June,
毎年11月にやらせていただいております
I'm allowed to hold this in November every year.
なので今日も実質誕生日でございますね
So today is practically my birthday too, isn't it?
はい おめでとう
Yes, congratulations.
ありがとうございます
Thank you very much.
そして本日のハッシュタグはこちら
And today's hashtag is this:
#夏色まつり誕生祭2025 でございます
#NatsuiroMatsuriBirthdayFestival2025
いっぱいツイートして トレンドに入れてあげてください
Please tweet a lot and help get it trending.
お願いします
Please!
スクショとかもね あの撮っていただいたりとか
If you take screenshots,
あとツイートしてくれたら
or tweet about it,
まつりちゃんが後でエゴサーチさせていただきますので
Matsuri-chan will ego-search for them later,
ぜひよろしくお願いしますね
so please do. Thank you!
見ちゃうよ
I'll be watching!
ということで まあみなさんもうお気づきかなと思います
So, I think everyone has noticed by now.
本日のタイトル「アイドル革命進行中」
Today's title: "Idol Revolution In Progress"
「今日の主役は夢の途中」
"Today's Protagonist is in the Middle of a Dream"
というタイトルにもあるようにでございますね
As the title suggests,
本日はアイドルさんの曲を
today I packed in a lot of songs
たくさん詰め込んだ
by various idols.
超とってもとっても可愛くて
It's going to be a super, very, very cute,
ポップでキュートで
pop, and cute,
ワクワクするようなライブになっていますので
and exciting live concert,
最後まで楽しんでいってくださいね
so please enjoy it until the end.
よろしくお願いします
Thank you!
コメントでもサイリウム振ったりとか
Please wave your cyalumes in the comments,
「可愛いよ」って言っちゃったりとか
and say things like "You're cute!"
たくさんしてくださいね
Please do it a lot!
ということでこのあとは皆さんお待ちかねの
So, coming up next is what everyone has been waiting for...
ゲストパート！
The guest part!
やったー！
Yay!
え ダンスとかがすごく大好きなので
I really love dancing, so...
あの レッスンでね
during the lessons,
「お願い やらせてください」って言って
I begged them, "Please let me do this,"
フォーメーションとかもね 含め
and including the formations and such,
みんなには頑張ってもらっていますので
everyone has been working really hard on it,
あの 君の推しがもしいたら褒めてあげてください
so if your favorite is here, please praise them.
ということで
So with that said,
え ゲストパート準備してきちゃいますね
I'm going to go get ready for the guest part.
じゃあみんな「わくわく」ってコメントして待ってて
Everyone, comment "waku waku" and wait for me.
じゃあ行ってきまーす
Okay, I'm off!
わくわく！
Waku waku!
わーくわくわくわくわくわく
Waaaku waku waku waku waku...
Hello P.M.P from Akihabara to everywhere
さそ寄ってらっしゃい見てらっしゃい も一切合切やっちゃいな
Come on over, take a look! Let's do it all!
有竹の渇いた楽しいこと詰め込んで
Pack in all the thirsty fun things we have!
妄想挿入 船に乗っていざ出航だ
Insert delusions, board the ship, and set sail!
Hello P.N.P from Japanese hot area
みんな元気でカッコつけて
Everyone, look lively and act cool!
はい 電波！
Yes, Dempa!
電波！
Dempa!
ありがサンキュー 準備はバッチリのようだね
Thanks, thank you! Looks like preparations are perfect.
今からでっかい船に乗っていざ出航だ
Now we board a huge ship and set sail!
さあみんな DANCE DANCE DANCE
Come on everyone, DANCE DANCE DANCE!
さらし巻いてビラがヒラリ
Wrap the sarashi, flyers flutter down.
カッコつけてもパッパッパとはみ出てる
Even if we act cool, it sticks out pa-pa-pa!
めちゃくちゃなときめいたり
Chaotically heart-throbbing,
それが僕らにとってのファンタジー
that is our fantasy.
シュントシュント感じるんだ呼んでるんだ
Feeling it sharply, it's calling us!
ソレソレソレソレ
Sore sore sore sore!
SHAKE SHAKE SHAKE
腕を振っては汗タラリ
Wave your arms, sweat dripping down.
ずっとしてもコチコチコチ逆方向
Even if you stay still, tick-tock, opposite way.
青春はそれでいいのだ
That's perfectly fine for youth!
勘違いも味方にしちゃうのだ
Make misunderstandings your ally too!
森羅万象 歌えニッポン 踊れニッポン
All creation! Sing Japan! Dance Japan!
あ ソレソレソレソレ！
Ah, sore sore sore sore!
チントンシャント どこまでも
Chin-ton-shan, on and on forever.
ほら パワフル全開で突き抜けろ
Look, break through with full power!
あっちもこっちもそっちも祭りだワッショイ
Here, there, and everywhere, it's a festival! Wasshoi!
アッパレアッパレ アドベンチャー
Bravo, bravo adventure!
大和撫子へ任せ
Leave it to the Yamato Nadeshiko,
不思議な言霊 奇想天外さ いつまでも
mysterious spirit of words, unpredictable forever!
神様仏様うさぎ様
God, Buddha, Rabbit-sama!
月に祈って拝んで君思って
Pray to the moon, worship, thinking of you.
半端な気持ちを断ち切って
Cut off those half-hearted feelings!
とりあえずいっか 黙ってついてこい
Whatever, just shut up and follow me!
Follow Me!
ああ…
Ah...
君の未来を明るく照らすなんて
To light up your future brightly,
お茶の子さいさいさい
is a piece of cake, sai sai sai!
百花繚乱 大和撫子たちよ
Profusion of flowers, oh Yamato Nadeshikos!
どでかい花火を上げましょね
Let's launch some huge fireworks!
ほら踊る阿呆に見る阿呆
Look, a dancing fool and a watching fool.
同じ阿呆なら踊らにゃ損損損
If we're both fools, you lose if you don't dance!
さあみんな DANCE DANCE DANCE
Come on everyone, DANCE DANCE DANCE!
さらし巻いておへそチラリ
Wrap the sarashi, glimpse of a belly button.
靴脱いだらソコソコソコ破れてる
Took off my shoes and the bottom is torn!
ドタバタなこのステージ
This slapstick stage,
これが私にとっての政治
this is politics to me!
妄想創造 羽ばたくんだ聞こえるんだ
Delusion, creation, taking flight, I can hear it!
ソレソレソレソレ
Sore sore sore sore!
SHAKE SHAKE SHAKE
腕を振っては涙キラリ
Wave your arms, tears twinkle.
強がってもキュンキュンキュン苦しいの
Even acting tough, my heart throbs, it hurts!
乙女はそれでいいのだ
That's perfectly fine for a maiden!
マイナスも味方にしちゃうのだ
Make the negatives your ally too!
チョイとそこ愛してんだみんな大好き
Hey you there, I love you! I love everyone!
ダダダダダダダ
Da da da da da da da
Break down!
チントンシャント どこまでも
Chin-ton-shan, on and on forever.
ほら パワフル全開で突き抜けろ
Look, break through with full power!
あっちもこっちもそっちも祭りだワッショイ
Here, there, and everywhere, it's a festival! Wasshoi!
アッパレアッパレ アドベンチャー
Bravo, bravo adventure!
大和撫子へ任せ
Leave it to the Yamato Nadeshiko,
不思議な言霊 奇想天外さ いつまでも
mysterious spirit of words, unpredictable forever!
神様仏様うさぎ様
God, Buddha, Rabbit-sama!
月に祈って拝んで君思って
Pray to the moon, worship, thinking of you.
半端な気持ちを断ち切って
Cut off those half-hearted feelings!
とりあえずいっか 黙ってついてこい
Whatever, just shut up and follow me!
Follow Me!
ああ…
Ah...
君の未来を明るく照らすなんて
To light up your future brightly,
お茶の子さいさいさい
is a piece of cake, sai sai sai!
満月の下で踊りましょ
Let's dance under the full moon!
桜舞い散る季節を歌いましょ
Let's sing of the season where cherry blossoms flutter!
君といつかまた出会うその日まで
Until the day I meet you again someday!
忘れない 忘れないで
I won't forget, don't you forget!
バイバイさようなら
Bye bye, sayonara!
時間たてば事務的にやってくる
Time just passes by methodically.
明日なんて我々の明日じゃない
Tomorrow isn't strictly our tomorrow.
逃げたい じゃあどこに
I want to run away, but where to?
逃げればいいのかな
Is it okay if I just run away?
曖昧な場所では
In such a vague place,
何にも変われない
nothing can ever change.
立ち向かえとかやり直せ
"Face it head on," "Start over,"
っていう方が間違った道を
people saying that make you redo
何度もやり直させる
the wrong path over and over.
あなた一体誰ですか？
Who exactly are you people?
論点ズレてる人達なんか
Push aside those people
押しのけて
who are missing the point,
自分の道作らなくちゃ
and pave your own way.
失敗しないなんて契約を人は
Humans haven't signed a contract
誰とも結んではいない
with anyone to never fail.
幸せになりますとは言えないいつか
I can't say "I'll be happy," but someday...
昔大事な人と約束したはずだ
I must have promised someone important long ago.
大人になるために
To become an adult,
早く忘れることだけ覚え
learning only to forget quickly.
無理に目を背けたら
If you forcibly look away,
10年後の君を救えないよ
you won't be able to save the 'you' 10 years from now.
全部自分が悪いと
To you who blames yourself
責める君に伝えたい
for everything being your fault,
同じ言葉を人に言わない君を
You, who wouldn't say those same words to others,
誰も責められない
no one has the right to blame.
逃げない じゃあどこに
I won't run away. But where to?
向かえばいいのかな
Where should I head towards?
辛さの根源を
A place where I can re-examine
見つめ直せる場所
the root cause of this pain.
いきなり空を飛ぶ
I don't know any method
方法なんて知らない
to suddenly fly through the sky.
悪と暇の行き来は
Don't go back and forth
誰ももうしないで
between vice and idleness anymore.
生きろとか蘇れとか
"Live!" "Revive!"
もういい もういい 逆に逃げて
Enough, enough. Run away instead.
もういいんだよとかいう私
The 'me' who says "It's fine now,"...
一体誰ですか？
...who exactly is that?
分かってくれている
There are people who proved
瞳の輝きが
that the sparkle in my eyes
消えてないって
that understands me
証明してくれた人たちがいる
has not disappeared.
時間たてば事務的にやってくる
Time just passes by methodically.
明日なんて我々の明日じゃない
Tomorrow isn't strictly our tomorrow.
足に訊ねる
Asking my legs,
走れるか
"Can you run?"
指に訊ねる
Asking my fingers,
開けるか
"Can you open it?"
体温に訊ねる
Asking my body heat,
血潮で導いていけるだろうか
"Can my blood lead the way?"
始まりの合図は
I don't want anyone else
他の誰も決めさせたくない
to decide the signal to start.
教科書の先の現代は
Because the modern era beyond textbooks
我々が作っていくから
is something we will create.
だから逃げない
So I won't run away.
私は逃げない
I won't run away.
逃げたい君を
I won't leave you behind,
置いてはいかない
you who want to run.
じゃなきゃ意味ない
Otherwise there's no meaning.
話したいことない
There's nothing I want to talk about.
顔見なくなって
I don't see your face anymore,
君を知ってる
but I know you.
苦しめる渦の中
Inside the tormenting vortex,
頭脳の目広げて
open your mind's eye wide.
別の角度で見てごらん
Try looking at it from a different angle.
そこだけ逃げないで
Just don't run away from that.
時間たてば事務的にやってくる
Time just passes by methodically.
明日なんて我々の明日じゃない
Tomorrow isn't strictly our tomorrow.
とくべちゅして
Do something special (Tokubechu).
Oh baby 'I love you' じゃ足りない
Oh baby, 'I love you' isn't enough.
一番大事がいい
I want to be the most important one.
君が作るオリジナルの
The original one that you create,
特別、チューして
give it a special kiss.
眩しくて目が覚めて
It's dazzling and I wake up,
愛おしく思ってよ
think of me lovingly.
眠り姫のように
Just like Sleeping Beauty,
優しく口付けて
kiss me gently.
ゴミめいたこの世界
In this trash-like world,
ピュアがかる君がいる
there is you, tinged with purity.
全てに触れずに
Without touching everything,
2人だけでいよう
let's be just the two of us.
私のこと独占して
Monopolize me,
君だけのモノになってもいい
I'm okay with becoming yours alone.
なんでもある日の
On any ordinary day,
「なんでもない」気付いてね
realize that 'it's nothing'.
Oh baby 'I love you' じゃ足りない
Oh baby, 'I love you' isn't enough.
君の「特別」にして
Make me your 'special one'.
ねぇもっと Give me a kiss
Hey, more, give me a kiss.
もう私は君でいっぱいよ
I'm already full of you.
ほどけないリボン結び
A ribbon knot that won't come undone,
小指キュッて縛って
tie our pinky fingers tight.
そうよ一生一緒がいいもん
That's right, I want to be together for life.
とくベチュが欲しい
I want a special kiss.
2人きり週末は
On the weekend with just us two,
奏でてよハーモニー
play a harmony.
流れ星見たら
If you see a shooting star,
私を想ってほしい
I want you to think of me.
あまあまな君なのに
Even though you are so sweet,
広い街 吸い込まれ
swallowed up by the wide city,
戦う姿に
for your fighting figure,
大きい花丸だね
you get a big gold star.
好きなところ、優しいとこ
What I like about you is your kindness.
嫌いなとこも、優しいとこ
What I dislike is also your kindness.
誰にもあげない
I won't give you to anyone.
私だけ独り占め
You're mine all to myself.
う〜だって 今までの人と
Ooh, because with everyone until now,
同じはいらないんです
I don't need the same thing.
ねぇもっと Give me more love
Hey, more, give me more love.
私のため生きてほしいんです
I want you to live for my sake.
だから ウサギと私は
That's why, the rabbit and I,
さみしくさせないで
don't make us feel lonely.
そんなんじゃ束縛じゃないわ
That's not being possessive.
苦しいのが好き
I like it when it's suffocating.
ショートケーキ イチゴみたいに
Just like a strawberry on a shortcake,
座ってもいい？
can I sit there?
赤く甘い恋だもん
Because it's a red, sweet love.
積み上げた
The things we piled up,
大好きも
the 'I love yous' too,
返してもらって全部私に
give them all back to me.
ちょーだい
Give it to me.
もっと！
More!
君は神様が作る
You are a creation of God,
奇跡のようなヒト
a person like a miracle.
拗ねた顔も その寝顔も
Your pouting face, and your sleeping face,
守ってあげるね
I'll protect them, okay?
Yeah
Oh baby 'I love you' じゃ足りない
Oh baby, 'I love you' isn't enough.
君の「特別」にして
Make me your 'special one'.
ねぇもっと Give me a kiss
Hey, more, give me a kiss.
もう私は君でいっぱいよ
I'm already full of you.
ほどけないリボン結び
A ribbon knot that won't come undone,
小指キュッて縛って
tie our pinky fingers tight.
ねぇ baby 最初で最後の
Hey baby, the first and the last...
とくベチュにしてね
...make it a special kiss.
ミルクで乾杯
Cheers with milk.
コドモなら甘い
It's sweet for a kid.
レンジでチンしてあったかい
Warm it up in the microwave.
Let's go ぱぴぷぺPOP
Let's go Pa-Pi-Pu-Pe POP.
人生バンザイ
Hurrah for life!
この先10年安泰
Secure for the next 10 years.
漏れてバズったらハンパな〜い
If it leaks and goes viral, it's insane!
Let's go ぱぴぷぺPOP
Let's go Pa-Pi-Pu-Pe POP.
ぱぴぷぺPOP
Pa-Pi-Pu-Pe POP.
ビュンビュンです
It's zoom zoom.
ルンルンです
It's happy happy.
キャピキャピです
It's bubbly bubbly.
Happyです
It's happy.
問題ないっす
No problem.
半端ないっす
It's extreme.
我々ディスコティックなバンビーナ
We are discotic bambinas.
適当です
It's whatever.
イーシーです
It's easy.
曖昧です
It's ambiguous.
ずっとこうやって
Doing this forever.
ぱぴぷぺぽな感じで
With a Pa-Pi-Pu-Pe-Po feeling,
ポップに生きていこう
let's live life pop-style.
ぱぴぷぺPOP
Pa-Pi-Pu-Pe POP
Hi Hi
ぱぴぷぺPOP
Pa-Pi-Pu-Pe POP
Hi Hi
毎日毎日パーティー
Every day, every day is a party.
People let me hear dancing
横ノリで縦ノリで
Groove sideways, groove vertically,
ワルノリで
get carried away.
Oh yeah
映画のキャストみたいに
Like a movie cast.
ボンキュッボンなbody
A curvy body.
ハジケテ smile delight
Burst open, smile delight.
なんでスネてんの？
Why are you sulking?
うるさい！
Shut up!
なんで泣いてんの？
Why are you crying?
あっち行って！
Go away!
なんでなんで？
Why, why?
だってだって？
But, but?
女の子だもん
Because I'm a girl.
なんで怒ってんの？
Why are you angry?
わかってよ 言わなくても
Understand me, even if I don't say it.
わかってよ
Understand me!
あ、ごめん
Ah, sorry.
やっぱ好き！
I love you after all!
めんどくさっ
So troublesome.
キュンキュンです ピュンピュンです
My heart's throbbing, zooming around.
ルンルンです 却下です
Humming along, rejected.
ハッピーです
I'm happy.
問題ない ハンパない
No problem, it's intense.
我々ディスコティックな
We are a disco-tic...
バンビーナ
Bambina.
テキトーです イージーです
Whatever, it's easy.
曖昧です ずっとこうやって
It's ambiguous, always like this.
パピプペポな感じで
With a Papi-pu-pe-po feeling,
POPに生きていこう
Let's live POP-style.
パピプペポ
Papi-pu-pe-po!
ハイハイ！
Yes, yes!
パピプペポ
Papi-pu-pe-po!
ハイハイ！
Yes, yes!
パッと咲いてShy
Blooming suddenly shy,
ピアニシモでKiss
Kissing with pianissimo.
古いラップよ
It's an old rap, you know.
ペプシ飲んで「あ～」
Drink Pepsi and go "Ah~"
ポップに踊ろう
Let's dance pop-style.
それ Let's Go
So, Let's Go!
Funny Funny Time
ペッペケペッペ ペッペケペッペ
Peppe-ke-peppe Peppe-ke-peppe
きゅんです 3・2・1
Finger heart! 3, 2, 1!
ペッペケペッペ ペッペケペッペ
Peppe-ke-peppe Peppe-ke-peppe
あこです 3・2・1
Over there! 3, 2, 1!
ペッペケペッペ ペッペケペッペ
Peppe-ke-peppe Peppe-ke-peppe
笑顔で 3・2・1
With a smile! 3, 2, 1!
ペッペケペッペ ペッペケペッペ
Peppe-ke-peppe Peppe-ke-peppe
変顔 3・2・1
Funny face! 3, 2, 1!
なんかいい感じ？
Feeling good?
もしもーし？
Hello?
なんか嬉しいな
I'm kinda happy.
もしか～ん？
Maybe?
なんか なんか やっぱ やっぱ
Somehow, somehow, after all, after all,
女の子だもん
I'm a girl.
なんかハッピーです
I'm kinda happy.
うん、そんで？
Yeah, and so?
なんか有頂天です
I'm kinda ecstatic.
あ～もう幸せです
Ah, I'm just so happy.
聞いてよ
Listen to me!
幸せです
I'm happy!
ちょっと話ってことさ
Just a little talk,
聞いてー！
Listen!
へ～そうなんだ…
Heh, is that so...
最高です 絶頂です
It's the best, the peak.
ミラクルです スマートだです
It's a miracle, it's smart.
ハイパーです
It's hyper.
とんでもない 尋常ない
Unbelievable, extraordinary.
我々アーティスティックな
We are an artistic...
パピーじゃん
Puppy, aren't we?
ちょっとだけボンクラです
Just a little bit of a dimwit.
大概です ずっとこうやって
Mostly like this, always like this.
パピプペポな感じで
With a Papi-pu-pe-po feeling,
POPに生きていこう
Let's live POP-style.
パピプペポ
Papi-pu-pe-po!
ミルクで乾杯
Cheers with milk!
砂糖混ぜたら甘ーい
Add sugar and it's sweeet~
レンジでチンしてあったかーい
Zap it in the microwave and it's warm~
Let's Go パピプペポ
Let's Go, Papi-pu-pe-po!
人生バンザイ
Hurrah for life!
この先10年安泰
Peace and quiet for the next 10 years.
これでバズったらハンパない
If this goes viral, it'll be insane.
Let's Go パピプペポ
Let's Go, Papi-pu-pe-po!
愛チュセヨ Loving you
Give me love, Loving you.
アモーレ アミーゴ
Amore, Amigo.
ABCDEFGHIJKLMNO
People
Poppin!
Be Poppin!
最大級 最高級 最上級
The greatest, the highest grade, the supreme,
ハイスペックな人生です
high-spec life!
I love you, I for you
だけでも君がいないと悲しいな
But it's sad without you.
ほんとはね やっぱね
Actually, after all,
結局ね ずっとこうやって
in the end, always like this.
パピプペポな感じで
With a Papi-pu-pe-po feeling,
POPに生きていたい
I want to live POP-style.
パピプペポ
Papi-pu-pe-po!
キュンキュンです ピュンピュンです
Heart's throbbing, zooming around.
パピプペポな感じで
With a Papi-pu-pe-po feeling,
POPに生きていこう
Let's live POP-style.
POPに Enjoy
Enjoy POP!
あれこれそれどれ 楽しいね
This, that, and everything is fun!
ハイハイ！
Yes, yes!
POPに Enjoy
Enjoy POP!
あれこれそれどれ 楽しいね
This, that, and everything is fun!
ハイハイ！
Yes, yes!
みんな ゲストパートどうだった？
Everyone, how was the guest part?
可愛かった？ ありがとうございます！
Was it cute? Thank you!
ということでね すごい続けてやってしまったんですが
So, we did a lot of songs in a row,
まず『サクラあっぱれーション』は
first, for 'Sakura Apparition',
あずきとルーナちゃんと莉々華に出てもらいました
I had AZKi, Luna-chan, and Ririka appear.
なんかすごい桜というか春っぽいね
I called members who fit the 'Sakura'
ピンクな感じのメンバーをね 呼びました
or spring-like pink theme.
莉々華すごい頑張ってたよなー
Ririka really worked hard, didn't she?
すごいね練習中も「あ～できない～」って言いながらね
Even during practice, she kept saying "Ah~ I can't do it~"
頑張ってた莉々華
but she did her best, Ririka.
そして次『逃げない！！』
And next, 'Nigenai!!'.
『逃げない！！』はちょっと結構古めの曲なんですけど
'Nigenai!!' is actually quite an old song,
まつりがすごいすごい大好きで 一番推していたゆるめるモ！さんのね楽曲で
but it's a song by Yurumerumo! that I absolutely love and supported the most,
あの ここで歌えてすごく嬉しかったです
so I was really happy to be able to sing it here.
ありがとうございますね
Thank you very much.
そして『特別して』
And 'Tokubetsu shite'...
はもう難しかった！
...was so difficult!
すごい難しかったんだから！
It was really difficult, I tell you!
だってさ 1番と2番さ
Because, you know, the 1st and 2nd verses,
サビの振りも違うし​​さ
the chorus choreography is different too.
めちゃ難しかったよ
It was super hard.
いや =LOVEさんの曲は毎回難しいけど すごい踊ってて楽しいでございますね
Well, =LOVE's songs are always difficult, but they are really fun to dance to.
はい そして『パピプペPOP!』
Yes, and 'Papi Pu Pe POP!'...
これ あの ずっとこうやってやってるから
This one, we're doing this the whole time,
すごい疲れて
so it was really tiring,
あの… 汗だくになったｗ
um... I got soaking wet with sweat. (Laughs)
もう凄かったよ
It was amazing.
練習中の時も汗だく過ぎて
Even during practice, we were sweating so much,
ちょっと待って… ちょっと疲れたとか言ってね みんなで
saying "Wait a sec... I'm a bit tired" together.
わちゃわちゃしながらね 練習もしましたけど
We practiced while having fun chaotically,
すごい楽しかったでございます
but it was really fun.
そしてちょっと紹介できてなかった こちらのステージ！
And I haven't introduced it yet, this stage!
じゃーん！ 可愛い！
Ta-da! It's cute!
すっごい可愛くね 作っていただきました
They made it incredibly cute for me.
うーん ソングたちばかりなので
Hmm, since it's just full of songs...
アイドルステージっていう感じにしてくださいって言ってね
I asked them, "Please make it feel like an 'Idol Stage'!"
こんな感じになりましたよ
And it turned out like this!
あの提灯もね あるけどさ
There are paper lanterns too, but...
なんかすごい あの 主張しすぎないというか
They aren't overly assertive, you know?
いい意味でね
In a good way.
あの なんかパステルなピンクとか
Like with the pastel pinks...
ま これ色変わるんですけど
Well, these actually change color...
すごい可愛い感じにしてくれて
They made it look super cute for me.
でね 風船もね
And the balloons too...
これね 色変わるんですよ 実はね
These actually change color, believe it or not.
なんかちょっとそこの辺も注目していただきたいなと思いますね
I'd love for you to pay attention to that part as well.
めっちゃ可愛いですよ
It's super cute, isn't it?
あの後で 一個だけ持って帰らせてもらおうかなと思います
I think I might take just one home with me later.
はい そして
Okay, and then...
あのね みんな気づいてなかったかなと思うんですけど
I wonder if maybe you guys didn't notice, but...
あのね まつりすがねいるわけですよ
You see... the Matsurisus are here!
そう あのね周年 1期生の周年ライブの時にはいなかったんですよ
Right, during the Gen 1 Anniversary Live... they weren't there!
ね エビフライオンがねいたの代わりに
Right? Ebi-fry-lion was there instead.
他のさ はあとんとかはさ あの...
Even though other fan mascots like the Haatons...
ちゃんとはあとんとしていたのに リスナーさんの姿でいたのに
...were properly there as Haatons, in the listeners' form...
まつりだけね まつりすがいなくて エビフライオンだったんで
Only Matsuri didn't have Matsurisu and had Ebi-fry-lion...
今回 あの よかったねこれって
So this time... isn't this great for you guys?
ということで
So with that said...
早速 続いての曲いきましょうか
Shall we move on to the next song right away?
続いては アイドルソングでございますよ
Next up is an Idol Song!
それでは聴いてください アイドルソング
Please listen. "IDOL SONG".
ねえアイドルになりたい
Hey, I want to become an idol
すごい愛をあげたい
I want to give lots of love
この命の使い道を
The way to use this life...
君に愛されたい
...is to be loved by you.
はい！行くわよ今の私アナ！
Okay! Here I go, the current me!
宇宙一にさせちゃうぞ！
I'll make you number one in the universe!
埼玉県から来ました！
I came from Saitama Prefecture!
フレッシュレモンになりたいの！
I want to become a Fresh Lemon!
ファンの方が恋人です！
My fans are my lovers!
真面目なアイドル 真面目にアイドル
Serious idol, seriously doing idol
年中無休 24時間 ずっと笑顔で嘘つき
Open year-round, 24 hours, always lying with a smile!
はい あなたの心にホールインワン！
Hai! Hole-in-one in your heart!
あなたのハートにアクセスします！
I'm accessing your heart!
みんなのドキドキにシュートします！
I'm shooting into everyone's excitement!
何でもいいからレスください！
Anything is fine, so please respond!
ハゲ気味なみなさーん！
All you balding folks out there!
うぉーーーい！
Whoaaa-i!
よし 今日も可愛い
Alright, cute again today.
小指ビーム！
Pinky Beam!
ねえアイドルになりたい
Hey, I want to become an idol.
本当は分からないけど
I don't really understand it, but...
幸せに見えてるシャボンの
Instead of being a soap bubble...
代わりを見つけたの
...that just looks happy, I found a replacement.
歌で人の気持ち
If I can brighten...
明るくできるように
...people's feelings with songs...
きっと人生に挫けてる
Because I think there are people...
人がいると思うから
...who are discouraged in life.
好きでいいよ
It's okay to like me!
もっと簡単に
More simply!
好きでいいよ
It's okay to like me!
もっと叫べ
Scream more!
好きでいいよ
It's okay to like me!
もっと簡単に
More simply!
好きでいいよ
It's okay to like me!
もっと叫べ イェイ！
Scream more! Yay!
はい！ めちゃくちゃ話すのが苦手
Hai! I'm super bad at talking!
可愛い自分 気持ち悪ぅ...
Acting cute feels gross...
説明などいらん 歌って踊って
No explanation needed! Just singing, dancing...
破壊する！
...and destroying!
萌える瞳 萌える髪の毛
Moe eyes, Moe hair!
見た目は純白 中身は真っ黒
Pure white appearance, pitch black inside!
ちょっぴりおバカな 小さな巨人
A slightly foolish little giant!
完成でしょう！
That's perfection, right?!
はい 見ることは見る気を混ぜるだけ
Hai! Just mix seeing with the will to see!
あっという間に ミルキー！
In a blink of an eye, Milky!
ちちんぷいぷい 魔法にかーかれ
Chichin-puipui! Be cast under a spell!
あっ かかっちゃった！
Ah! You got caught!
トイレなんて行ったことないよ
I've never been to the bathroom!
ピンクのマシュマロが出ます
Pink marshmallows come out!
３時のおやつは マカロンが良い
I want macarons for my 3 PM snack!
ふわふわガール メジャー志向！
Fluffy girl, aiming for the majors!
ねえアイドルが楽しい
Hey, being an idol is fun.
いっぱい愛が舞ってる
There's so much love fluttering about.
ステージから見る景色が
The view from the stage...
ずっと宝物さ
...will always be my treasure.
ねえもし君が高い
Hey, even if you paid...
支払いしたとしても君が
...a high price...
引くような分の幸せは
...I've given you enough happiness...
あげられていたかな
...to make you recoil, right?
好きでいいよ
It's okay to like me!
もっと大胆に
More boldly!
好きでいいよ
It's okay to like me!
もっと叫べ
Scream more!
好きでいいよ
It's okay to like me!
もっと大胆に
More boldly!
好きでいいよ
It's okay to like me!
もっと叫べ ふぅー！
Scream more! Woo!
はい！ 360度どこから見ても？
Hai! 360 degrees, wherever you look?
アイドル！
Idol!
出席番号 ラッキーセブン！
Roll call number, Lucky Seven!
好きになってもいいですか？
Is it okay if I fall for you?
僕の妹がこんなに可愛いわけがない担当！
In charge of "My Little Sister Can't Be This Cute"!
プリップリ！ ピチッピチでしょコーンニチネギネギー！
Fresh and bouncy! Peachy and lively, right? Kon-nichi-negi-negi!
押せる 愛せる ランドセル
Supportable, lovable, school satchel!
今日も明日も明後日も
Today, tomorrow, and the day after too!
キラキラパワー全開！
Sparkling power, full throttle!
がんばっていきまー
Let's do our...
しょーい！
...best!
みんなの目線は？
Everyone's gaze is?
いただきまゆゆ！
Itadaki-Mayuyu!
浮気して 甘えん坊な
Cheating, spoiled...
みんなの妹！
...everyone's little sister!
ねえアイドルが楽しい
Hey, being an idol is fun.
いっぱい愛が舞ってる
There's so much love fluttering about.
アイドルの見習い
An idol apprentice,
すごい愛はあげたい
I want to give you amazing love.
この命の使い方を
How should I use this life?
君に愛されたい
I want to be loved by you.
好きでいいよ　もっと簡単に
It's okay to like me, more simply.
好きでいいよ　もっと叫べ
It's okay to like me, scream it more!
好きでいいよ　もっと簡単に
It's okay to like me, more simply.
好きでいいよ　もっと叫べ
It's okay to like me, scream it more!
好きでいいよ　もっと大胆に
It's okay to like me, be more bold!
好きでいいよ　もっと叫べ
It's okay to like me, scream it more!
優しさ　絆　キラキラ輝け
Kindness, bonds, sparkle brightly!
頑張っていきまー
Let's do our be-
しょーい！
-st!
わぁ！
Wah!
びっくりしたでしょ？
Surprised you, didn't I?
今日の私が
That I'm...
昨日より可愛いなんて！
...cuter today than I was yesterday!
ぎゅっち　ぎゅっちゅ　ぎゅっちして
Hug-kiss, hug-kiss, give me a hug-kiss.
次の流行りは次の時代
The next trend is the next era.
踏まないように知っとかなくちゃ
Gotta know so you don't step on it.
でもぎゅっちしたら大爆発
But if we hug-kiss, it's a big explosion.
知りたい知りたい　死にたくない
Want to know, want to know, don't want to die.
知りたくない　ずっとどうしたら
Don't want to know, what should I do forever?
なぜなぜ　わからない
Why, why, I don't understand.
堕落こそワンダーランド
Depravity is truly a wonderland.
私　ち　ち　ち　ち
I'm chi-chi-chi-chi...
ちんぎゅ　私　ち　ち　ち　ち
...chin-gyu! I'm chi-chi-chi-chi...
ちんぎゅー
...chin-gyu!
ぎゅー！
Gyu!
過去再燃焼
Past re-ignition.
未来数年先
A few years into the future.
過去最大ら
Greatest 'la' in history.
未来蹴っ飛ばら
Kick away the future 'la'.
未来チラチラ
The future is flickering.
福袋みたい
Like a lucky bag.
好きな色が見えたから
I saw my favorite color,
これにしよーかな
so maybe I'll pick this one?
だ　て　ら　イェーイ！
Da-te-ra, yay!
ちゅーぎゅー
Chu-gyu!
じゅぎゅー！
Ju-gyu!
歌うわしないならしちゃう辞苑
If you don't sing, I'll make you, dictionary.
間違っても可愛くなれる知恵
Wisdom to be cute even if you make a mistake.
一番可愛い時に死にたい
I want to die when I'm at my cutest.
なら全然死ねないね
Then you can't die at all, huh.
私　ち　ち　ち　ち
I'm chi-chi-chi-chi...
ちんぎゅ　私　ち　ち　ち　ち
...chin-gyu! I'm chi-chi-chi-chi...
死んでる暇ない　可愛いと言いたい！
No time to be dead, I want to say I'm cute!
過去最年長
Oldest in history.
未来数年少
Youngest for years to come.
今捨てた子
The child abandoned now,
未来全部入り
includes all the future.
素敵な君が
You, who are wonderful,
好きな私で
with me, who I like.
奇特すごく素敵な
Unique, very wonderful...
女の子になー
...becoming a girl-
るのも！
-too!
何歳になっても可愛いね、じゃないの
It's not 'You're cute regardless of age'.
こっちは努力して可愛いやってんの！
I'm working hard to be cute over here!
何十何歳だったら可愛いの？
At what twenty-something age is it 'cute'?
本当はそんなの当たり前だもん
Really, that's just a given.
言わせないでよ
Don't make me say it.
そっちが言って
You say it.
今日も可愛いね！
You're cute today too!
でしょ？
Right?
今日も可愛いね！
You're cute today too!
可愛いね！
You're cute!
可愛いー！
Cuuute!
今日も可愛い！
Cute today too!
今日も可愛いー！
Cute today too-!
私、今日も可愛いね！
I'm cute today too, right!
よし、今日も可愛いぞ
Alright, I'm cute today too.
未来チラチラ
The future is flickering.
終わりや老いは
The end and old age,
覗き見しては
I peek at them,
元に戻して
and then put them back.
未来チラチラ
The future is flickering.
怖いからこそ
Precisely because I'm scared,
今をもっと極に生きたい
I want to live this moment more extremely.
過去最年長
Oldest in history.
未来数年少
Youngest for years to come.
過去最大ら
Greatest 'la' in history.
未来蹴っ飛ばら
Kick away the future 'la'.
未来チラチラ
The future is flickering.
福袋みたい
Like a lucky bag.
好きな色が見えたから
I saw my favorite color,
これにしよーかな
so maybe I'll pick this one?
だ　て　ら　イェーイ！
Da-te-ra, yay!
ちゅーぎゅー
Chu-gyu!
じゅぎゅー！
Ju-gyu!
だ　て　ら
Da-te-ra!
君にポイな　恋のS.O.S
I toss you an S.O.S of love.
ずっと胸が苦しいんです
My chest has been painful for a while.
早くレスキュー
Hurry, rescue me!
好きになれば　死に
If I fall in love, I'll die...
早く気付いて
...hurry and notice!
初めて出会った時から
From the moment we first met,
ハートが震えてたんだよ
my heart was trembling.
無意識に意識しちゃう
I'm unconsciously conscious of it.
この感じは重症です
This feeling is serious.
見つめ合うだけで顔が熱いの
Just looking at each other makes my face hot.
話しかけられて頭が
When you talk to me, my head...
甘い毒めいた言い逃れ
Sweet poison-like excuses.
いいの？ 拗ねた気持ちは
Is it okay? My sulking feelings.
君との相性診断
Our compatibility diagnosis.
星占いなら So good So good
If it's horoscopes, it's So good, So good.
友達なんかじゃないよ
We're not just friends.
ときめいてる
My heart is throbbing.
キミにFall in love 恋のSOS
Falling in love with you, SOS of love.
ずっと胸が苦しいんです ハヤクRescue
My chest has been aching, quickly Rescue me.
「好き」のテレパシーに早く気づいて！
Notice my telepathy of 'love' quickly!
これはFall in love 恋のSOS
This is falling in love, SOS of love.
もっとキミに近づきたい
I want to get closer to you.
終わらせて 片想いMy heart
End this unrequited love, My heart,
全部抱きしめて
Embrace it all.
キミが好きな音楽や
The music that you like,
映画のことリサーチして
And movies, I research them all.
SNS見るたびに イイネ押すの アピールだよ
Every time I see your SNS, I press Like. It's an appeal!
四六時中キミのこと考えて
Thinking about you 24/7,
妄想しながら枕ギュってした
I hugged my pillow while fantasizing.
明日はどんな服着ていこうかな
What kind of clothes should I wear tomorrow?
キミ想うだけでなんか照れる
Just thinking of you makes me blush.
キミの名前を呼べば
If I call your name,
ただそれだけでも Dreaming Dreaming
Just that alone makes me Dreaming Dreaming.
溺れそうな私を
Me, who is about to drown,
助け出して
Rescue me.
キミにFall in love 恋のSOS
Falling in love with you, SOS of love.
ずっと胸が苦しいんです ハヤクRescue
My chest has been aching, quickly Rescue me.
「好き」のテレパシーに早く気づいて！
Notice my telepathy of 'love' quickly!
これはFall in love 恋のSOS
This is falling in love, SOS of love.
もっとキミに近づきたい
I want to get closer to you.
終わらせて 片想いMy heart
End this unrequited love, My heart,
全部抱きしめて
Embrace it all.
生まれたてのトキメキを響かせよう
Let's make this brand new excitement resound.
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
With the best time and the best friends.
キラメキに乗って
Ride on the sparkles.
覚えてるかな？ 最初の歌
Do you remember? Our first song.
私の声が震えていた
My voice was trembling.
あの日から続く未来は
The future that has continued since that day,
みんなと掴んだ今日だよ
Is today, which we grasped together with everyone.
もっともっともっともっと
More, more, more, more,
加速するハート
My accelerating heart.
一緒に行くよどこまでも
I'll go with you, anywhere.
準備はOK？
Are you ready?
ひらけ 夢のトビラを
Open up! The door to dreams!
キラメキライダー
Kirameki Rider.
重ねた手はギュッと離さずに
Holding our joined hands tightly without letting go.
ひとり違う 描き出すトキメキ
Each of us sketches a different excitement.
振り向くことなくまっすぐに
Without looking back, straight ahead,
行くよ 夢見る空へ
Let's go, to the dreaming sky.
笑い合ったことや
The things we laughed about together,
尽きそうにない話題
Topics that never seem to run out,
思い出いっぱいなのに
Even though we have so many memories...
One, Two
みんなのため力になる
It becomes power for everyone's sake.
歩く… わぁ！
Walking... Waah!
今日も賑やかすぎるくらい
Today is almost too lively.
笑顔がもう止まらない
The smiles just won't stop.
想いは膨らんでいく
Feelings are swelling up.
重ねて今 ぎゅっと噛み締めた
Layering them now, holding them tight.
一人 時間
Time alone...
歌声は広がる
the singing voice expands.
風を感じたら真っ直ぐに
If I feel the wind, straight ahead...
行くよ
Here I go!
夢見る空へ
To the dreaming sky.
背伸びしては手を伸ばす
Standing on tiptoes, reaching out my hand.
憧れの行き先示す星になろう
Let's become the star that shows the longed-for destination.
つまずくその度に
Every time I stumble,
手を差し伸べ合えたら
if we can reach out to each other,
すぐに届くはずさ
we should reach it soon.
そっと踏み出した 小さな勇気が
The small courage I gently stepped forward with,
もう消えないように繋げよう
let's connect it so it won't vanish.
不安も愛しさも大切に抱きしめて
Embracing both anxiety and dearness carefully.
共に行くよ
We'll go together!
目を合わせて Three Two One
Meet eyes, Three Two One!
晴れ渡る希望へ
To the clear hope,
飛び出せるよ
we can jump out!
突き抜けていく
Breaking through,
僕たちの透き通る決意は
our transparent determination.
まだまだ止められないよ
Can't be stopped yet!
ありきたりな今日こそ
Even this ordinary day,
ときめきに変えて
turn it into excitement.
もっと
More!
僕たちがいつまでも
We will always,
背中押すから
push your back!
憧れの舞台立ちたいらしく輝きたい
I want to stand on the stage I admire, shine in my own way.
時に涙してまた笑い合いたい
Sometimes shedding tears, wanting to laugh together again.
同じ未来を見たい あの夢手にしたい
Want to see the same future, want to grasp that dream.
踏み出そう 奇跡の一歩を
Let's take that miraculous step forward.
息切らして夢追いかけたい ワクワク止まらない
Out of breath, want to chase the dream, excitement won't stop.
想像越えてく世界見せてあげる
I'll show you a world that exceeds imagination.
アクセスしてみたい？ 後悔なんてここにない
Want to try accessing? There are no regrets here.
それぞれ違ったココロで
With each of our different hearts,
作る World
create a World.
はい！ということで
Yes! So,
ホロライブ… 言いにく… ホロライブメドレー
Hololive... hard to say... Hololive Medley.
自分の主催なのに… でした！
Even though it's my own event... that was it!
いやどうだった？なんか激エモだったんじゃないですか？
How was it? Wasn't it super emotional?
そしてね この衣装は初めてもらったアイドル衣装なんですよ
And, this outfit is the first idol outfit I ever received.
なんかあの時を思い出して なんかすごいジーンときてしまいますわね
It makes me remember that time and feel really moved.
まつりはね 元々そのアイドルデビューじゃなかったんですよ
Matsuri wasn't originally an idol debut, you know,
ホロライブって
in Hololive.
で この衣装をもらって
So receiving this outfit,
よし アイドルとして頑張るぞというね
made me think, 'Alright, I'll do my best as an idol.'
気持ちを改めて思い出し
I'm remembering that feeling anew,
頑張っていこうかなという気持ちでございます
and I want to keep doing my best.
そしてそして 今回も
And, and, this time too,
誕生日グッズ出ちゃいます！やったー！
Birthday goods are coming out! Yay!
嬉しい！
I'm happy!
ということで一つずつ紹介していきます
So, I will introduce them one by one.
まずは… こちら！ドどん！
First is... this! Do-don!
「薄すぎ！おっぱいマウスパッド」… あ おっぱいマウスパッド！
'Too thin! Boob mouse pad'... Ah, boob mouse pad!
やったー！
Yay!
イラストはえく先生
Illustration by Eku-sensei.
まつりす… 待望のね マウスパッドでございますよ
It's the mouse pad... the Matsuris have been waiting for.
もうあの ちなみに言うと
Just to mention, by the way,
膨らみは… ないです
there is... no swelling.
普通のマウスパッドとなっております
It is a standard mouse pad.
薄すぎ！おっぱいマウスパッド！
Too thin! Oppai Mouse Pad!
なんですが... ちょっとガチ照れな...
However... I'm actually really shy about this...
きゃっ！みたいな感じなのでね
It's got a 'Kyaa!' sort of vibe,
あのもう心から癒されていくという感じで
so you can just be healed from the bottom of your heart.
はい、どうですか？素晴らしいことでございましょ？
Yes, how is it? Isn't it wonderful?
そして続いてこちら！じゃーん！
And next is this! Tada!
ランダムアクリルキーホルダー！
Random Acrylic Key Holder!
なんと夏色まつり先生のね、書き下ろしでございますよ
Surprisingly, it's a new illustration by Natsuiro Matsuri-sensei!
ランダムアクリルキーホルダー
Random Acrylic Key Holder.
もうまつりがね、グッズのイラスト描くってなかなかないでございますから
It's rare for Matsuri to draw illustrations for goods,
すごい愛称込めて描きました
so I drew them with a lot of love.
もうチュチュチュってしながら描いたのでね
I drew them while going 'chu chu chu',
ぜひね全種類コンプリートしてみてください
so please try to complete all types.
そして続いてこちら！
And next is this!
じゃーん！
Tada!
まつりちゃんのぬいぐるみ サブカルジャージ衣装バージョンでございます
It's Matsuri-chan's Plushie, Subculture Jersey Outfit Version!
キービジュのねイラストと同じサブカルジャージの衣装の
It's the same subculture jersey outfit as the key visual illustration,
なんとぬい！が登場しちゃいますよ
and surprisingly! A plushie is appearing!
キービジュのように押し倒すことはちょっと現実だと叶わないけど
Pushing me down like in the key visual isn't possible in reality,
ぬいなら！ぬいならできちゃう！ということで
but with the plushie! With the plushie, you can do it!
ぜひねたくさん可愛がっていろんなとこに連れて行ってあげてください
So please love it a lot and take it to various places.
さらにこちら！
Furthermore, this!
まつりすマグカップ！
Matsurisu Mug Cup!
みんなにはマグカップになってもらいました
I had everyone become a mug cup.
どんな罪を犯してこんな姿になっちまったんだ！
What kind of sin did I commit to end up in this form?!
て感じでございますが（笑）
Is how it feels, but (laughs).
まあ自分なのでね、あのこれが俺の姿かと思いながら
Well, since it's yourself, while thinking 'Is this my form?'
使っていただけたらなと思います
I hope you use it.
まつりちゃんも使わせていただきます
Matsuri-chan will also use it.
最後に
Lastly,
ボイス！じゃじゃーん
Voice! Ta-da!
シチュエーションボイス「逆襲のまつりす」
Situation Voice 'Counterattack of the Matsurisu'.
なんだ逆襲のまつりすってなんだ？
What? What is 'Counterattack of the Matsurisu'?
はい今回ねキービジュのシチュエーションに至るまでのストーリーが
Yes, this time, the story leading up to the key visual situation
ここに詰まっちゃってますので
is packed in here,
どんなシチュエーションなのかちょっと気になる方はぜひゲットしてみてください
so if you're curious about what kind of situation it is, please get it.
そして！
And!
フルセットを購入いただいた方全員に
For everyone who purchases the Full Set,
直筆サイン＆箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカードがついてきちゃいます
it comes with a handwritten autograph & foil-stamped message postcard.
えーちょっとね来年は直筆やるかちょっとまだ未定でございますので
Um, it's still undecided if I'll do handwritten ones next year,
ぜひね、ぜひぜひぜひぜひ
so please, please please please please,
全員に書かせていただきますので
I will write for everyone.
初めてなんですよそれも
It's the first time for that too.
全員にサイン書くの初めてだから
Since it's the first time I'm writing autographs for everyone,
ぜひ手に入れてください
please get it.
来年やるかわかんないからね
I don't know if I'll do it next year.
さらにですね！
Furthermore!
こちら！タレントプレミアムグッズのフルセット特典として
Here! As a Full Set bonus for Talent Premium Goods,
2024年9月から発売されたホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームで使用できるカードが
a card usable in the Hololive Official Card Game released in September 2024
一枚ついてきちゃいますよ
is included!
まつりはね前回のグッズでちょっと特典についてなかったので
Matsuri didn't have it as a bonus in the previous goods,
今回ついてくるよって感じになっております
so this time it's included.
え、どうふうする... どうふうであってる日本語？
Eh, enclosed... is 'enclosed' the right Japanese?
ホロライブプロダクションオフィシャルショップで購入されたお客様のみの対象となっておりますので
It is only available to customers who purchased at the Hololive Production Official Shop,
よろしくお願いします
so thank you.
特典につくのはゲームで一枚だけ使用でき
The bonus is a card that can be used only once in the game,
推しをアピールできるキーカード、推しホロメンカードでございます
and allows you to appeal your oshi, the Oshi Holomem Card.
そしてそしてそして！さらにでございますよ！
And and and! There's even more!
まだある！アルバム！
Still more! Album!
デデデデデデデン
Da-da-da-da-da-da-dan!
なんとまつりちゃん 1st アルバム
Surprisingly, Matsuri-chan's 1st Album
Chasing the Dream スポットライトは放課後に
'Chasing the Dream: Spotlight After School'
が、なんと！本日、受注開始でございます！
is, surprisingly! Starting orders today!
ぱんぱかぱーん！
Pan-paka-pan!
まつりちゃん初のオリジナル楽曲「君と眺める夏の花」をはじめ
Starting with Matsuri-chan's first original song 'Kimi to Nagameru Natsu no Hana',
これまでに配信リリースしてきた作品に加え、
along with works released digitally so far,
じんさんはじめ豪華作曲陣が書き下ろしてくださった
and new songs written by gorgeous composers like Jin-san,
新曲も収録しちゃってますよ
are also included.
計14曲の超ボリューミーなアルバムになっているので、ぜひ手に入れちゃってください！
It's a super voluminous album with a total of 14 songs, so please get it!
コンセプトはね、アイドルのまつりちゃんと
The concept is the idol Matsuri-chan
普段の女子高生のまつりちゃんのこう両面みたいな？
and the usual high school girl Matsuri-chan, like both sides?
両方が楽しめるようなアルバムになってます
It's an album where you can enjoy both.
形態は二つありまして
There are two versions:
完全生産限定盤と、えー通常盤をご用意しております
Fully Limited Production Edition and Regular Edition.
完全生産限定盤はですね
The Fully Limited Production Edition
セパレートタイプのオリジナルカレンダーがついてきちゃいますよ
comes with a separate-type original calendar.
そして両形態に封入特典として
And included in both versions as a bonus,
まつりちゃんからの複製お手紙が入っています
is a reproduction letter from Matsuri-chan.
ただし！数量限定のランダムでですね
However! Randomly in limited quantities,
複製お手紙の代わりに
instead of the reproduction letter,
直筆お手紙がもらえちゃう案内が封入されていますので
information on how to get a handwritten letter is enclosed,
ぜひぜひゲットしちゃってください！
so please definitely get it!
以上、アルバム情報でした！
That's all for the album information!
残りの一曲をですね 本日このあと披露しちゃいます！
I'm going to perform the last remaining song right now!
タイトルは… ウーニャカ！ ニャニャニャー！
The title is... U-nyaka! Nya nya nya!
作曲はですね かいりきベアさんに作曲いただきました！
The music was composed by Kairiki Bear-san!
めちゃめちゃ可愛い！
It's super cute!
MVもですね このあとプレミア公開ありますので
There will also be a music video premiere after this,
えー0時から あの 楽曲リリースもありますので
and the song will be released at 12:00 AM,
あのーぜひ よろしくお願いしますね
so please check it out.
プレミア公開も一緒に見ようね はい！
Let's watch the premiere together, okay? Okay!
じゃあちょっと着替えてきますので ちょっとここで待ってて
I'm going to go change now, so please wait here.
ワクワクって言いながらね あのゲストパートと同じようにワクワクって言いながら待ってて下さい
Just like during the guest part, please wait while saying 'Waku waku'.
じゃ行ってきます！
I'm off!
ワクワク…
Waku waku...
ウーニャカ
U-nyaka
真夜中にトケタ感情は爪立てて
Emotions melted in the dead of night sharpen their claws
塔から見慣れた世界は牙向いて
The familiar world seen from the tower bares its fangs
真夜中見かねた感情は飢えた目で
Emotions unable to watch the dead of night, with hungry eyes
軽やかに逃げた優しさ求めて
Seeking the kindness that lightly escaped
「愛されたい」の想い 愛されないの Give me
The desire to 'be loved', not being loved, Give me
「愛してる」も重い？ 愛さえないの？ もういい？
'I love you' is too heavy? No love at all? Are we done?
愛情結晶頂戴 あなたを見てるのニャ
Give me the crystal of affection, I'm looking at you, nya
ニャンニャカリンリンリン おねだり
Nyan-nyaka rin-rin-rin, begging you
さあ手懐けてよ もっと めいっぱーい
Come on, tame me, more, with all your might
ニャンニャカリンリンリン おでかけ？
Nyan-nyaka rin-rin-rin, going out?
しがみついて何処も行かせない！
I'll cling to you and won't let you go anywhere!
ウーニャカニャンニャ ウーニャンニャン
U-nyaka nyan nyan, u-nyan nyan
甘いキャンディ頂戴な
Give me sweet candy
ウーニャカニャンニャ ウーニャンニャン
U-nyaka nyan nyan, u-nyan nyan
ハッピーライフ頂戴な
Give me a happy life
ウーニャカニャンニャ ウーニャンニャン
U-nyaka nyan nyan, u-nyan nyan
叱らないで頂戴な
Please don't scold me
ウーニャカニャンニャ ウーニャンニャン
U-nyaka nyan nyan, u-nyan nyan
ほんとの「好き」頂戴な
Give me your true 'love'
縄張り土足で感情目丸くして
Stepping into territory with shoes on, emotions wide-eyed
幸せになれた未来が牙向いて
The future where I could have been happy bares its fangs
突き放さないでいて切り捨てず傍で
Don't push me away, don't cut me off, stay by my side
お傍でお傍で見ているのニャ
I'm watching from your side, from your side, nya
ニャンニャカリンリンリン おねがい
Nyan-nyaka rin-rin-rin, please
さあ頭撫でて もっと ぜーいっぱーい
Come on, pat my head, more, with all your might
ニャンニャカリンリンリン おあずけ？
Nyan-nyaka rin-rin-rin, wait command?
甘えて泣いて 此処に居させて！
Let me act spoiled and cry, let me stay here!
ニャンニャカ言ったって伝わんない？
Even if I say nyan-nyaka, it doesn't get through?
どーしたってこーしたって寂しいの
No matter what I do, I'm lonely
ニャンニャカリンリンリン おもいっきり
Nyan-nyaka rin-rin-rin, with all my might
あざとい声 わざと聞かせる
I purposely let you hear my cutesy voice
ニャンニャカリンリンリン おねだり
Nyan-nyaka rin-rin-rin, begging you
さあ手懐けてよ もっと めーいっぱーい
Come on, tame me, more, with all your might
ニャンニャカリンリンリン おやすみ？
Nyan-nyaka rin-rin-rin, goodnight?
しがみついて今夜寝かせない！
I'll cling to you and won't let you sleep tonight!
ウーニャカニャンニャ ウーニャンニャン
U-nyaka nyan nyan, u-nyan nyan
甘いキャンディ頂戴な
Give me sweet candy
ウーニャカニャンニャ ウーニャンニャン
U-nyaka nyan nyan, u-nyan nyan
ハッピーライフ頂戴な
Give me a happy life
ウーニャカニャンニャ ウーニャンニャン
U-nyaka nyan nyan, u-nyan nyan
抱きしめて頂戴な
Please hug me
ウーニャカニャンニャ ウーニャンニャン
U-nyaka nyan nyan, u-nyan nyan
ほんとの「好き」頂戴な
Give me your true 'love'